[
   {
      "question":"Who assassinated Grahavarmana, the brother in law of Harshavardhan ?",
      "optionA":"Shashanka of Gauda",
      "optionB":"Kirtivarman",
      "optionC":"Chandragupta",
      "optionD":"Narsimhavarman",
      "correctAns":"Shashanka of Gauda"
   },
   {
      "question":"Who defeated Harsha Vardhana on the banks of river Narmada in 630 A.D.?",
      "optionA":"Pulakesin II",
      "optionB":"Mahendravarman I",
      "optionC":"Pulakesin I",
      "optionD":"Kirtivarman I",
      "correctAns":"Pulakesin II"
   },
   {
      "question":"In Sangam age, the book ‘Bharatam’ was written by__?",
      "optionA":"Perudevanar",
      "optionB":"Manimekalai",
      "optionC":"Seethalai Saathanaar",
      "optionD":"Tiruttakrdeva",
      "correctAns":"Perudevanar"
   },
   {
      "question":"In the Later Vedic period, who was the god of Shudras?",
      "optionA":"Pushan",
      "optionB":"Prajapati",
      "optionC":"Agni",
      "optionD":"Indra",
      "correctAns":"Pushan"
   },
   {
      "question":"At which of the following sites, largest variety of food grains in the Chalcolithic age has been found?",
      "optionA":"Navdatoli",
      "optionB":"Gilund",
      "optionC":"Adamgarh",
      "optionD":"Banahali",
      "correctAns":"Navdatoli"
   },
   {
      "question":"Pushkalavati was capital of which of the following acient Kingdoms?",
      "optionA":"Gandhara",
      "optionB":"Kosal",
      "optionC":"Magadha",
      "optionD":"Kashi",
      "correctAns":"Gandhara"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following passes was used by Sakas to come to India?",
      "optionA":"Bolan Pass",
      "optionB":"Nathu La Pass",
      "optionC":"Shipki La Pass",
      "optionD":"Bara-lacha la Pass",
      "correctAns":"Bolan Pass"
   },
   {
      "question":"Who among the following rulers of Gupta dynasty started Gupta Era?",
      "optionA":"Vishnugupta",
      "optionB":"Chandragupta I",
      "optionC":"Skandgupta",
      "optionD":"Samudragupta",
      "correctAns":"Chandragupta I"
   },
   {
      "question":"Buddhacharita, the epic biography of Gautama Buddha in Sanskrit was written by__:",
      "optionA":"Asvaghosa",
      "optionB":"Indrabhuti",
      "optionC":"Asanga",
      "optionD":"Bodhisena",
      "correctAns":"Asvaghosa"
   },
   {
      "question":"Mundaka Upanishad, the Mandukya Upanishad and the Prashna Upanishad are associated with which of the following Vedas?",
      "optionA":"Atharva-Veda",
      "optionB":"Rig-Veda",
      "optionC":"Sama-Veda",
      "optionD":"Yajur-Veda",
      "correctAns":"Atharva-Veda"
   },
   {
      "question":"Mahamaya', the mother of Gautama Buddha belonged to which among the following dynasties?",
      "optionA":"Shakya",
      "optionB":"Koliyan",
      "optionC":"Lichchavi",
      "optionD":"Maurya",
      "correctAns":"Koliyan"
   }
]